

Lexington, KY 859.955.0841 ellewhitedev@gmail.com www.ellewhite.dev linkedin.com/in/ElleWhiteDev

# Elle White

## Career Objective

With over a decade in IT roles and a recent dive into full-stack development, my passion is firmly rooted in backend work. Seeking a junior backend position, I'm eager to blend my IT legacy with new development skills. I value deep knowledge, team collaboration, and clear communication. Ready to contribute innovation, enthusiasm, and adaptability in a growth-focused role.

## **Technical Skills**

- HTML5 | CSS 3
- Javascript | JQuery
- React | Node
- Python | Flask
- mySQL | postGRESQL
- AWS | Apache | Linux

## **Additional Skills**

- Visual Studio Code
- Command Line
- Github
- Jira | Confluence
- Insomnia | Postman



## **Education**

2023

**Springboard** 

Software Developer/ Fullstack Engineer Trainee



### BACKEND DEV

## **Work Experience**

#### **Associate Support Engineer**

PlanetBids, Remote Jan 2024 - Present

- Spearheaded customer support initiatives, efficiently resolving tickets related to database information and user history
- Innovated web scraping strategies for vendor identification and engagement, resulting in a 100% increase in our vendor database and significantly expanding our market reach and business opportunities in new states

#### **Asst Dir/ Preschool Teacher**

Early Learning Center, Winchester KY 2018 - 2022

- Designed and implemented a unique, tailored curriculum in a self-created classroom environment, successfully aligning with state preschool standards while catering to the diverse needs of special education students
- Oversaw operational aspects and coordinated multidisciplinary teams in a special needs daycare setting, cultivating skills in project management, team collaboration, and problem-solving

#### **Engineer**

Interkek, Lexington KY 2014 - 2016

 Conducted comprehensive EMC evaluations on diverse products including IoT devices, medical equipment, and industrial devices, ensuring compliance with U.S., Canadian, and International standards; managed project elements from testing to client communication

#### **Quality Improvement Specialist**

Amazon, Lexington KY 2012 - 2014

- Assisted in the establishment of a customer service call center
- Authored comprehensive training decks and SOPs for Kindle call flow that has since been implemented across the nonnetwork
- Developed an intuitive 'hours worked' tool, which was adopted across the local site